export const data = {
  quizequestions: [
    {
      question:
        "Q1: Which of the following is the correct syntax to print the message in C++ language?",
      a: 'cout <<"Hello world!";',
      b: " Cout << Hello world! ;",
      c: "Out << Hello world!;",
      d: " None of the above",
      ans: "ans1",
      category: "clanguage",
    },
    {
      question: "Q2: Which of the following is the correct identifier?",
      a: " $var_name",
      b: " VAR_123",
      c: " varname@",
      d: " None of the above",
      ans: "ans2",
      category: "clanguage",
    },
    {
      question: "Q3: Which of the following is the address operator?",
      a: " @",
      b: " #",
      c: " &",
      d: " %",
      ans: "ans3",
      category: "clanguage",
    },
    {
      question:
        "Q4: Which of the following features must be supported by any programming language to become a pure object-oriented programming language?",
      a: " Encapsulation",
      b: " Inheritance",
      c: " Polymorphism",
      d: " All of the above",
      ans: "ans4",
      category: "clanguage",
    },
    {
      question:
        "Q5: The programming language that has the ability to create new data types is called___.",
      a: " Overloaded",
      b: " Encapsulated",
      c: " Reprehensible",
      d: " Extensible",
      ans: "ans4",
      category: "clanguage",
    },
    {
      question:
        "Q6:Which of the following is the original creator of the C++ language?",
      a: " Dennis Ritchie",
      b: " Ken Thompson",
      c: " Bjarne Stroustrup",
      d: " Brian Kernighan",
      ans: "ans3",
      category: "clanguage",
    },
    {
      question:
        "Q7:Which of the following is the correct syntax to add the header file in the C++ program?",
      a: " #include < userdefined>",
      b: ' #include "userdefined.h" ',
      c: ' < include > "userdefined.h " ',
      d: " Both A and B",
      ans: "ans4",
      category: "clanguage",
    },
    {
      question:
        "Q8:Which of the following is the correct syntax to read the single character to console in the C++ language?",
      a: " Read ch()",
      b: " Getline vh() ",
      c: " get(ch) ",
      d: " Scanf(ch)",
      ans: "ans3",
      category: "clanguage",
    },
    {
      question:
        "Q9:Which of the following statements is correct about the formal parameters in C++?",
      a: " Parameters with which functions are called",
      b: " Parameters which are used in the definition of the function ",
      c: " Variables other than passed parameters in a function ",
      d: " Variables that are never used in the function",
      ans: "ans1",
      category: "clanguage",
    },
    {
      question: "Q10:The C++ language is ______ object-oriented language.",
      a: " Pure Object oriented",
      b: " Not Object oriented",
      c: " Semi Object-oriented or Partial Object-oriented ",
      d: " None of the above",
      ans: "ans3",
      category: "clanguage",
    },
    {
      question:
        "Q11:Which of the following comment syntax is correct to create a single-line comment in the C++ program?",
      a: " //Comment",
      b: " /Comment/",
      c: " Comment// ",
      d: " None of the above",
      ans: "ans1",
      category: "clanguage",
    },
    {
      question: "Q12:C++ is a ___ type of language.",
      a: " High-level language",
      b: " Low-level language",
      c: " Middle-level language ",
      d: " None of the above",
      ans: "ans3",
      category: "clanguage",
    },
    {
      question:
        "Q13:For inserting a new line in C++ program, which one of the following statements can be used?",
      a: " \\n",
      b: " \\r",
      c: " \\a ",
      d: " None of the above",
      ans: "ans1",
      category: "clanguage",
    },
    {
      question: "Q14:Which one of the following represents the tab?",
      a: " \\n",
      b: " \\t",
      c: " \\r",
      d: " None of the above",
      ans: "ans2",
      category: "clanguage",
    },
    {
      question:
        "Q15:Which of the following refers to characteristics of an array?",
      a: " An array is a set of similar data items",
      b: " An array is a set of distinct data items",
      c: " An array can hold different types of datatypes ",
      d: " None of the above",
      ans: "ans1",
      category: "clanguage",
    },
  ],
};
